James Idiens

Software Developer

027 4783 767

Merivale, Christchurch

,

New Zealand Citizen

in

LinkedIn

<u>Github</u>

Portfolio http://bitly.ws/PBtU

About Me:

I'm a software developer with a background in business management and a Bachelor of Commerce qualification. I have a passion for problem-solving and learning new technologies, and I'm enthusiastic about finding a role where I can integrate my technical and business expertise. With a solid foundation in communication and interpersonal skills, I thrive in collaborative team environments. Please feel free to explore my portfolio, linked above, for a deeper insight into my development projects.

Experience:

Dev Academy Aotearoa (March 2023 - July 2023)

Student Fullstack Software Developer

- Completed a 15-week full-immersion full stack development course closely simulating a real-world development experience. Equipped with a solid foundation to contribute effectively to modern development teams and deliver impactful solutions.
- Developed proficiency in modern technologies including; JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, React, Redux, Knex, SQL Databases, Node.js, and Express.js.
- Experienced working in teams using the Agile/Scrum methodology
- For our final group project my idea was selected, and I took on the role of Product Owner making critical
 decisions and prioritizing tasks for maximum value. Our team built a modern ecommerce website which
 can be viewed here. I implemented Stripe's API which allowed payment processing for products.

August 2023 to Current:

Electoral Commission - Ilam HQ Support

Jan 2020 to October 2022:

Pak 'N Save, Wainoni

Online Manager (Jul 2022 to Oct 2022)

- Selected to oversee and manage the project launch of the new Online Shopping Division
- Recruited staff, delivered training and the ongoing provision of coaching for team members
- Developed and implemented new systems, using SAP for managing stock and procurement

Duty Manager (Jan 2020 to Jul 2022)

- Managed the entire store in the absence of the Store Manager
- Led and managed the daily operations of 20 plus staff including recruitment and training
- Completed various administrative duties, including production of a range of management reports

Education:

New Zealand Certificate in Applied Software Development (Level 6)

Dev Academy Aotearoa (2023)

Bachelor of Commerce Degree, majoring in Management with a Minor in Marketing:

- University of Canterbury, Christchurch (2015 to 2018)
- Awarded the University of Canterbury Emerging Leaders Development Programme Scholarship

Secondary Schooling:

- Christ's College, Christchurch (2010 to 2014)
- NCEA Levels 1, 2, 3 and UE

Work Related Training Completed:

Foodstuffs South Island Leadership Academy - Principles of Leadership (2021)

Skills and Competencies:

- Analytical approach with a critical thinking style, with very strong problem-solving skills often developing resourceful ideas
- Able to engage with people at all levels and from various backgrounds, developing and maintaining excellent ongoing working relationships with customers, colleagues, decision makers and stakeholders
- Uses initiative, capable of working autonomously, self-managing, leading or working within a team
- Strong communication skills including very good verbal, written and group presenting capabilities delivering clear and concise information
- Fast learner as demonstrated by progress of learning full stack development in 15 weeks

Out of Work Interests:

- My main passion is guitar. I also enjoy piano, reading and writing
- Getting out on the golf course, following sport (especially rugby), and leading an active lifestyle
- Spending time with friends and family

Referees:

• Referees are available on request